本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流之用 更多中日双语字幕，请登录 www.kamigami.org  台本：卷 　翻译:mam  校对: maize　时间轴：那年夏天  后期：娜夏
ご苦労だったな
This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
ゆっくり休んでいいぞ
はい
Good job!
Get some rest.
お台場よ 私は帰ってきた
Yes.
鹿児島から ２０時間 トラックに乗りっ放しで お尻が痛いよ
Odaiba! I'm back!
After a 20 hour drive from Kagoshima in that truck, my butt hurts.
あしたの開場は９時 ロボットの搬入は ８時から受け付けだって
The doors open at 9 AM tomorrow.
ということは 今日は ここまでってことか
We can bring in the robot after 8 AM.
よし 宿に行くぞ お前ら
That means everything's done for today.
ホントに宿だよね？
Okay, let's go to the hotel.
We're really staying at a hotel?
何 このベッド
Ahaha! Look at this bed!
見て こんなに転がっても平気だよ
ミッチー 奮発してくれたんだね ちょっと見直したよ
Wow, it's fluffy! Look!
I can roll about all I want!
そうだねぇ 一部屋だけど
気持ちいい
Mitchie must've really gone out of his way for this! I've gotta re-evaluate him!
渡された鍵は１つだけ これはダブルベッド
Yeah. Though we've only got one room.
It feels so great!
Only one key.
And a double bed.
ちなみに 不純異性交遊は 退学の対象だ  これ 豆な じゃ
By the way, engaging in illicit sexual relations will result in expulsion from the school.
ホント ミッチー使えない…
Just saying.
Later.
Just how useless can he get?
どうする
どうするって…
うちは平気だけど カイは？
What do we do now?
"What do we do now?" you say...
俺も 別に問題なし
I don't mind, but do you?
だよね よかった
I don't really mind either...
いつ以来だろうね 同じ布団で寝るの
Okay then. Phew.
How long has it been since we last slept in the same bed?
残酷なる時は いつか
In the end, time unforgiving
契約の地さえ引き裂くの
たくさんが生み出す恐怖
Will draw the blood of covenant
Everything scatters, leaving void
真理のために今ここにいるよ
意外なCrazy
But we're here for the greater good
We Meet
目眩くこのシーン うかつな選択
Crazier than everyone, we need to dazzle
The stage with our careless justice
浮かび行く景色はやがて鮮やかに
And the scenery floating by becomes clearer
時間をすり抜ける
咆筺のメシア
As the Messiah of the Shoutbox slips through time
笑って 泣いて
僕らの一つの夢
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
願って 叫んで
どこまでも遠くへ
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
走って 飛ばして
気持ちの集まる場所
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
Run and break that place where feelings gather
愛しすぎるこの空の下で
Under this sky, oh so dear
明日を証明したくて
We're fighting for the future
カイ～ お風呂 全然 お湯が たまらない
Kai, I can't get the water deep enough!
いいホテルっていうのは みんな そんな感じなの
Good hotels are all like that.
Why?
何で
Who knows?
さあ
The true Gunvarrel's in there!
The "Kimijima Report" texts were distributed yesterday to PokeComs all around the world.
先日 世界中のポケコンに送信された 君島レポートなる文章
これは いったい 何なのか 単なる いたずらなのか
What are these texts? Is this just a prank, or did someone leak government secrets?
それとも 何者かが 国家機密を漏えいしたのか  謎は深ま…
Mysteries are getting dee—
タジリン
TAGIRIN?
この動き… やっぱり…
Those moves... It's the same...
ミサ姉… ミサ姉なんだろ？
Misa... Are you Misa?
逃げるなよ どうして逃げるんだよ
Don't keep running... Why are you running?
瑞榎さんが… 瑞榎さんが死んだんだぞ
Mizuka... Mizuka died!
That's right.
そうだね
Mizuka?
瑞榎さん…
どうして あのとき 助けてくれなかった
Why didn't you help me?
You just kept watching. So cold.
目の前で見ていたのに 冷たいじゃないか
Mizuka!
瑞榎さん
瑞榎さーん
Mizuka!
Aki...
アキちゃん…
Are you okay? You were mumbling in your sleep...
大丈夫？ うなされてたよ 起こしたけど 起きなくて…
You wouldn't wake up even when I tried to wake you.
I had a really bad dream.
嫌な夢をね… ２０時間も 車に揺られてたからかな…
It must be because of those 20 hours in the truck...
シャワー浴びてくるよ
I'll take a shower.
Kai...
カイ…
汗臭いよ 俺
I must stink.
カイって いつも へらへらして 本心 絶対 出さないよね
You just laugh everything away and never show your true feelings.
そうかな…
I guess...
苦しいときは 苦しいって言ってよ
When you're in pain, say so.
And anyway, we're never together recently...
それでなくても 最近 何か いつも別々で…
カイ １人で どっか行っちゃったり 何か １人で悩んでたり…
You always go alone somewhere,
or struggle with your problems alone...
Aki...
アキちゃん…
You didn't want to talk about it, so I didn't mention it,
言いたくなさそうだから 気付かないふり してたけど
でも… ホントは力になりたい
but I want to help you...
I want to help you when it's hard for you.
カイが苦しいときは 力になりたいよ
ずっと 一緒だったんだもん
We've always been together.
I guess you think I couldn't help you even if I tried.
きっと カイは うちなんかじゃ力にならないって
思ってるのかもしれないけど…
じゃあさ 今日は もう 眠れそうにないんで
徹夜で起きてるのに 付き合ってくれない？
Then...
I don't think I'm gonna be able to sleep any more tonight,
so do you wanna pull an all-nighter with me?
駄目？
You don't?
ううん そういうことなら うちに任せて
If that's what it is, just leave it to me!
うってつけのものが あるから
I've got what we need for that!
まさか…
Huh? Don't tell me...
徹夜で 『ガンヴァレル』視聴マラソン
We can marathon Gunvarrel all night!
アキちゃんらしいや
That's so like you.
オーライ オーライ
All right! All right!
そういえば アキちゃんさ… ミサ姉から連絡あった？
By the way, have you heard from Misa?
No, nothing. She feels so... distant.
ないよ… 何かね まるで実体を感じないの
もう 存在しないんじゃないかって…
Does she even exist at all?
Space Candy
I doubt that would be the case.
そんなことないと思うけど
でも… 本当に生きてるのかなって…
But really, is she still alive?
エグゾスケルトン社 パワードスーツは
We at Exoskeleton hope that Powered Suits
自動車 ポケコンと同じようにより 身近に より 皆さまの生活に…
can become an essential part of your lives just like cars or PokeComs.
What's that?
何これ？
エグゾスケルトンのロボだよ
Exoskeleton's robot.
Movement System
The control system developed at our company
based on ergonomic studies received positive
reviews both in Japan and around the world.
This system has been further improved to
enable multi-leg movement.
SUMERAGI is...
The SUMERAGI concept model is the fruit
of Exoskeleton's long years' of research.
Our company focuses on nursing products, so the comfort and pleasure of people in need of nursing will always be our top priority. We poured all the experience and technology we have into building the SUMERAGI. Please witness the devotion and provess of Exoskeleton.
Main Body Frame
The mainframe is made out of a new kind of material
developed at our company that enables further
decrease in weight. It also makes it stronger
and more durable.
Movement System
The control system developed at our company
based on ergonomic studies received positive
reviews both in Japan and around the world.
This system has been further improved to
enable multi-leg movement.
SUMERAGI is...
The SUMERAGI concept model is the fruit
of Exoskeleton's long years' of research.
Our company focuses on nursing products, so the comfort and pleasure of people in need of nursing will always be our top priority. We poured all the experience and technology we have into building the SUMERAGI. Please witness the devotion and provess of Exoskeleton.
Movement System
The control system developed at our company
based on ergonomic studies received positive
reviews both in Japan and around the world.
This system has been further improved to
enable multi-leg movement.
SUMERAGI is...
The SUMERAGI concept model is the fruit
of Exoskeleton's long years' of research.
Our company focuses on nursing products, so the comfort and pleasure of people in need of nursing will always be our top priority. We poured all the experience and technology we have into building the SUMERAGI. Please witness the devotion and provess of Exoskeleton.
It's a concept model. It's called... SUMERAGI.
コンセプトモデルで 名前はＳＵＭＥＲＡＧＩだって
これが 介護補助に どう役立つんだろう
How can this be used for nursing at all?
コンセプトモデルですから
It's a concept model.
はい？
Excuse me?
It's just to show that we can build stuff like this too.
こんなのも造れます みたいなアピールですね
Um, my name's Senomiya Akiho.
あ… あの… うち 瀬乃宮あき穂っていうんですけど
Senomiya? Ah, Ms. Misaki's relative?
瀬乃宮…？ みさ希さんの
あの… 姉は ここに来たりしますか？
Um, is my sister coming here?
ええ 来ますよ わが社の大事な広告塔ですから
Yeah, she is. She's an important advertising image for us.
Really? When?
本当ですか？ いつですか？
I don't know exactly... But probably as soon as the Expo opens.
正確なことは…
でも 万博が始まったら すぐに…
She'll be here!
お姉ちゃん 来るんだ… ここに
We can show her the GunPro-2.
ガンつく２ 見せられるんだ
Aki!
アキちゃん
Let's put the GunPro-2 together!
ガンつく２ 組み立てる
まったく…
Oh, geez...
She really loves her sister...
お姉さんのこと 好きなんですね
Can I make a request?
一つ お願いがあるんですが
ミサ姉
Misa!
Kai?
カイ…
You're working this late?
こんな夜中まで仕事なんだ
諦めないで ５時間も粘ってて よかったよ
I'm glad I didn't give up and waited here five hours.
帰りなさい
Go home.
"Thank you."
「ありがとう」って…
瑞榎さんの最後の言葉 聞いてよ
Those were Mizuka's last words.
Hear them.
"Thank you for giving me the Powered Suit."
「パワードスーツを プレゼントしてくれて ありがとう」って…
瑞榎さん そう言ってた
Mizuka said that.
そう…
I see.
What the hell?
何だよ それ
瑞榎さんは死んだんだよ 暴走して…
She died!
It ran out of control... The Powered Suit you gave her!
ミサ姉の贈ったパワードスーツが 暴走して 死んだんだよ
She died!
Doesn't that make you feel anything?
何とも思わないの？
ミズのことは残念だったわ
I feel sorry for Mizu.
That's it?
それだけ？
何を言われても仕方ないわね
It's natural for you to act like this.
Get in.
乗りなさい
澤田って人が 君島コウについて聞きに来た
A man named Sawada came asking about Kimijima Kou.
He knew that I was there at the SS Anemone incident and that Kimijima Kou died...
俺が あねもね号事件の 被害者なのも君島コウが死んだことも 知ってて…
君島コウって何者なの？
Just who is this Kimijima Kou?
ミサ姉と どんな関係なわけ
What's he got to do with you?
じゃあ 愛理は？ 知ってるよね
Then what about Airi? You know about her, right?
夕方 病院で会ってきたよ 目覚めた 行舟 愛理と…
Yukifune Airi woke up, so I went to see her at the hospital last night.
Yukifune Airi
君島コウのことは 覚えてるけど ＡＩのことは
よく分かってないみたいで…
She remembers Kimijima Kou,
but she didn't know much about any AI.
目覚めてから 会いに来てくれたのは あなたが初めてです
You're the first one to visit me since I woke up.
今日の天気 分かる？
Do you know today's weather?
外は 晴れてるみたいですけど…
It looks sunny outside...
何も言えないってこと？
So you can't say anything?
じゃあ それでもいいよ
Okay, I don't care.
だったら せめて アキちゃんには ちゃんとしてよ
But at least act normal to Aki!
アキちゃん 何も知らないんだよ
She doesn't know anything!
ミサ姉の夢を かなえようと ミサ姉に追い付こうと
She's worked so hard all this time to fulfill your dream, just to catch up to you!
ずっと ずっと それだけを思って 頑張ってきたんだよ
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
Subject: I'm in Tokyo
To: Sister
I put together the GunPro-2 at the Expo today.
We're finally here. I hope you'll come see it too!
知ってるんでしょ？ 今 東京に来てるってこと
You know she's in Tokyo too, don't you?
なのに 何で そんなに突き放すんだよ
Why are you ignoring her like that?
突き放してなんか いないわ
I'm not ignoring her. I just told her the truth.
事実を言っただけ あの子は平凡過ぎるの
She's too ordinary.
私の意思を継いで ロボットを造るなんて無理なの
She can never follow my dream and build robots.
やったところで 自分の無力さを痛感するだけ
She'll only realize her powerlessness when she tries.
But...
そんな…
だから言ったのよ そんなアキを よろしくって
That's why I told you to take care of her.
ミサ姉…
Misa...
見てください この 人
Please look at all these people!
今日から あの 東京万博２０２０ 夢創造博が開催されます
The 2020 Tokyo Expo, the Expo of Dreams, opened today!
今回の万博の目玉は ずばり ロボット
Robots are at the center of this Expo.
別名 ロボット万博なんて 呼ばれているほどで
It's even called the Expo of Robots.
Giant robots from all around the world gather here to welcome the guests!
会場内には 世界中の巨大ロボットが集結し
大勢のお客さんを出迎えています
Impact!
インパクト…
Compared to that...
それに比べて…
Space Candy
Tanegashima Robotics Club
This should do it.
これで よし っと
後は お父さんの つてを頼って 作ってもらった
For the rest, we'll use the handheld laser charger that we got one of Dad's contacts to make.
この 特製の コンパクト型レーザー送電銃で…
Gunvarrel Construction Diary
あの子は 平凡過ぎるのよ
She's too ordinary...
ねえ カイ
Kai!
何？
What?
大丈夫？ 昨日 愛理に 会いに行った後 何かあったの？
Are you okay?
Did something happen after you visited Airi?
帰り 遅かったみたいだけど
You got back pretty late.
大丈夫 ちょっと 疲れが残ってるだけだよ
I'm fine. Just a bit tired, that's all.
Hey!
おい 何だよ このガンヴァレルって
The hell's this Gunvarrel shit?
Tanegashima Robotics Club
Space Candy Inc.
We built Gunvarrel
Prototype 2!
『ガンヴァレル』って あの 人殺しのスタッフが作ったアニメだろ？
Isn't Gunvarrel that crappy anime those murderers made?
何 そんなもん 引っ張り出してきてんだよ
Why'd you bring that shit here?
何だ？ お前ら
You got a problem?
うるせえ
Shut it!
ちょっ…
アキちゃん
Aki!
瀬乃宮妹
Younger Senomiya!
ミッチー…
Mitchie...
頭 打ってないか
Did you hit your head?
ありがと
I'm fine...
ったく とっとと やめろよ
Hmph, get lost...
This ain't a place for murderer robots...
不謹慎なんだよ 人殺しロボ
You bastards!
お前らあぁぁぁ
痛い 痛い… ちょっ…
何か悲しいな
That's so sad.
『ガンヴァレル』って そこまで嫌われちゃったのか
Do people hate Gunvarrel that much now?
The robot did nothing wrong...
ロボットに罪はないのにね
あの人…
Him?
ワイバーン Ｘマイナス９０分です
Wyvern, X-90 minutes.
了解
Roger.
エグゾスケルトン社 コンセプトモデル
The six legs of the SUMERAGI by Exoskeleton are controlled by a finger operating system!
ＳＵＭＥＲＡＧＩは この６本の足をフィンガーオペレートシステム
つまり 指で動かしているんです
Whoa!
すげー
Amazing!
Come and see!
おじゃりもうせー
おじゃり？
See what?
種子島ロボ部 これより起動します
The Tanegashima Robotics Club is launching!
Let's first talk about the story of how this robot was built!
それでは まず このロボットができた経緯から お話しします
今から おおよそ９年前
Nine years ago, the project to build an actual Gunvarrel was started.
実物大ガンヴァレルを造ろう プロジェクトがスタートしました
もちろん 今 ガンヴァレルを
モデルにすることはこのタイミングでは よくないことというのは…
Of course, it's not the best idea to bring up Gunvarrel's name right now—
Aki, that'll be way too long of a story.
アキちゃん その話 長くなる？
Huh?
お客さん どんどん いなくなってるよ
No one's listening anymore.
But talking about the miracle of love and courage and glory would have the most impact!
でも うちらの愛と勇気と栄光の 軌跡を語った方がインパクトが…
It'd have none.
ないよ まったく
ボインパクト
そのとおり
Precisely.
じゃあ…
Then...
では ガンつく２ 起動せよ
Launch the GunPro-2!
前進
Move forward!
かに歩き
Crabwalk!
パパ カッコ悪い
Dad, it's so uncool...
I guess...
そうだな
はーい カッコ悪いとか言ってる そこの子
Hey you there, who just said it's uncool!
だまされたと思って 「居ル夫」で ガンつく２を見てください
If you think we fooled you, look at GunPro-2 through Iru-O!
The true Gunvarrel's in there!
そこに 本物のガンヴァレルが います
マジで？
何？ 本物？
ガンつく２ 撃砕第１
GunPro-2! PulverPunch No. 1!
元気一発
Genki Punch!
疾風怒濤の
Lightning Speed Genki Power Punch! Gunvarrel!
元気一発 ガンヴァレル ジャキーン
Yay!
ガンヴァレルじゃなければな
If only it wasn't Gunvarrel.
タカシ 行くぞ
Takashi, we're going.
But I wanna see it more!
もっと見てたい
No. Mom will get angry if she finds out you saw Gunvarrel.
駄目だよ ガンヴァレルを見せたなんて言ったらママに怒られちゃう
アキちゃん 気にしない
Don't worry about it, Aki.
Hey! Do it again! Again!
お姉ちゃん もう１回 もう１回 やってよ
元気一発 もう１回やってよ お願い お姉ちゃんってば
Do that Genki Punch thing again!
Pretty please!
Come on!
Lightning Speed Genki Power Punch! Gunvarrel!
疾風怒濤の 元気一発 ガンヴァレル
Yay!
ジャキーン
カイ？
Kai?
こ… こんにゃしは よろしく おにゃがいしまつ
Goof adternoom!
Thayk nou for mocing!
昴君じゃないんだから
You're not Subaru...
How is the feedback?
手応えは どうですか？
ま… まだまだ これからです
We've only just begun! We're taking the grand prize!
グ… グランプリ 取りますから
Oh, what a bold declaration!
大胆な宣言が飛び出しました
Senomiya Akiho's sister is the Misaki you can see in the Exoskeleton commercials as well.
瀬乃宮あき穂さんの お姉さんはエグゾスケルトン社のＣＭにも
出演されているみさ希さんですが
何か言っていましたか？
Did she have any comments?
No, nothing yet.
いえ まだ何も
Then let's call out to her!
じゃあ 宣言しちゃいましょうか もう
会場に いらっしゃるはずですから
She should be here at the Expo already.
Huh?
あれ？聞いてないんですか？
Hm? You didn't know?
No, I didn't....
いえ そ… そうですね
I see. This is Senomiya Akiho from the Tanegashima Robotics Club!
はい では 種子島ロボ部瀬乃宮あき穂さんでした
アキちゃん
Aki...
エグゾスケルトン社の控室って あっちだよね
The Exoskeleton changing room is that way, right?
待って
Wait!
Why?
どうして？
ミサ姉に会うのは もう少し先にした方がいい
You should meet with her sometime later.
どうして？ カイ 何か知ってるの？
Why? Kai, do you know something?
いや…
That's not it...
Authorized personnel only
アキちゃん アキちゃん 待って
Aki!
Aki, wait!
アキちゃん
Aki!
お… お姉ちゃん
Sis...
お姉ちゃん お姉ちゃん
Sis! Sis!
Hey, it's me, Akiho!
うちだよ あき穂だよ 覚えてる？
Do you remember? We are sisters, I guess...
って 姉妹なのに変だけど…
でも 最後に会ったの ７年前でしょ
It's been 7 years since we last met.
あのとき まだ うち 小学生で
I was still a grade schooler that time.
だから ほら… 見違えたでしょ？
You just didn't recognize me, right?
アキ 大きくなったわね
Aki, you've grown so big.
Yeah...
そうだ ロボ 見てくれた？ ガンつく２
Oh right, did you see the robot?
We built the GunPro-2 in the club, all together!
ロボ部のみんなで 造ったロボなんだよ
アキ 父さんと母さんは元気？
Aki, are Mom and Dad fine?
Yeah. Dad's really worked up about the new rocket launch after all these years.
お父さん 久々の ロケット打ち上げで張り切ってる
ミサ姉 こっち向いてよ
Misa, turn around!
今は そんなこと…
We can't just—
Senomiya Misaki!
瀬乃宮みさ希
あなたは…
You?
動くな
Freeze!
そのまま 手を上げろ
Hands in the air!
早く 手を上げるんだ
Raise your hands now!
Misa...
ミサ姉…
お姉ちゃん…
Sis...
アキ ロケットの打ち上げは まだ？
Aki! How long is it until that rocket launch?
聞いているのか 瀬乃宮 手を上げろ
Are you listening, Senomiya?! Raise your hands!
Sis!
お姉ちゃん
それはふとした瞬間に
All those unexpected moments
As you mumble on and on
君がつぶやくいくつもの言葉
Will overcome even my standards
それがいつしか価値観さえも
超えてしまうんだよ
In the end
All those goodbyes we said
いくつもの別れを告げ 僕らは
As we climb the stairway to the future
明日への階段をのぼる
とめどなく零れ落ちる雫も
Just as raindrops fall no matter what we do
光が照らすなら この星は繋がっている
Light will always hold this planet together
奇跡のように命が集まって
Lives gather as if by some miracle
Showing the outline of a lively scene
にぎやかな景色は輪郭になる
An epilogue so bright it brings tears to our eyes
泣きたい眩しいエピローグ
The sky painted by the hearts of those looking up
取り上げる思いが
描いた空
The wind blows gently stroking
柔らかな風が吹き
Turning into a new path
新しい道となり
A path that will always
いつだってその道は
Lead us to this place
この場所に繋がってる
Great occasion for a spoony bard, the sushi is.
Exactly!!
Tune in next week too!